Guide to the Julius Edelstein papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Correspondence, 1923-1960 (1950-1960)
  - Subseries III.1: Alphabetical, 1954-1960
    - J, 1956-1957 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - K, 1955-1958 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - L, 1954-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 2-3)
    - Lehman, Herbert H.--Memoranda, 1955-1958, (4 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 4-7)
    - M, 1957-1958 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - M, 1955-1958 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - N, 1955-1958 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - O, 1956-1958 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - P, 1956-1958 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Q, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - R, 1955-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 6-7)
    - S, 1955-1957, (2 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 8-9)
    - S1, 1956-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - T, 1955, 1957-1958 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - U through V, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - W, 1955, 1957-1958 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Y through Z, 1957-1958 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - A, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - B, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Backer, George and Evie, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Baumerder (Edelstein’s Parents), 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - C, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Cieplinski, Michel, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Cohen (various), 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - D, 1959-1960 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - E, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Edelstein, Rose, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Engel, Irving, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - F, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Fordham, Jefferson B., 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - G, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - H, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Halpern, Gerald P., 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Herzog, Yaacov and Penina, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Hession, Anne and John, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Hill, Lister, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - I, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - J, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - K, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Kollek, Theodore, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - L, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Lehman, Herbert H.--Memoranda to, 1959, (2 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 17-18)
    - Lehman, Herbert H.--Memoranda to, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Lehman, Herbert and Edith, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - M, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Marks, Edward B., 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Multiple Addressees, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - N, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - New York Committee for Democratic Voters, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - O, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - P, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Publications--Julius Edelstein’s Subscriptions, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Q, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - R, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - S, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Shultz, Lillie, 1958-1960 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Staff Memoranda, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Stern, J. David, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Sweeney, Esther E., 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - T, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - U through V, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - W, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Y through Z, 1959-1960 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Subseries III.2: Chronological, 1950-1960
    Comprised of a large amount of material from constituents expressing concern on a political issue or asking for the Senator’s help. As in all the other subseries in Series III, letters to and from various government officials are found throughout. The same political topics found in subseries III.1 are addressed with an emphasis on agriculture, civil rights and immigration.
    - 1950 April-December (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - 1951 January-October, December (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - 1952 Jenuary-December (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - 1953 January-July (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Telephone Notes, 1953 July-December (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - 1954 January-March, (2 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 7-8)
    - 1954 April-September, (6 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 1-6)
    - 1954 October-December, (3 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Telephone Notes, 1954 January-December, (2 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 4-5)
    - 1955 June, August (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - 1955 August-December, (6 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 1-6)
    - 1955 December (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Telephone Notes, 1955 January-December, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 2-3)
    - 1956 January, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 4-5)
    - 1956 February-April, (6 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 1-6)
    - 1956 May-September, (7 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 1-7)
    - 1956 October, (4 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 1-4)
    - Telephone Notes, 1956 January-October, (3 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 5-7)
    - 1957 January-August (Box 40, Folder 1-7)
    - 1957 September-December, (5 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 1-5)
    - 1958 March-May, (4 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 6-9)
    - 1958 June-December, (7 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 1-7)
    - 1959 January (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - 1959 February-September, (8 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 1-8)
    - 1959 October-December, (3 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 1-3)
    - 1960 January-August, (8 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 4-11)
    - 1960 September-December, (4 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 1-4)
  - Subseries III.3: Personal, 1923-1959 (1950-1959)
    includes both personal and professional correspondence. Many letters are with regard to Julius’s wife, Rivka and her health. Much of the correspondence is between Edelstein and both his family and Rivka’s parents in Israel. There is some material in Hebrew.
    - A, 1950-1954 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Americans for Democratic Action (ADA), 1951-1955 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Alinsky, Saul, 1954 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - B, 1948-1954 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Bensaude, Jose, 1950-1954 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - C, 1950-1954 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Cieplinski, Michel, 1950-1954 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Cunningham, Charles E., 1950-1951 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - D, 1950-1954 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - E, 1951-1954 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - F, 1950-1954 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Farrell, James T., 1950-1954 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Family, 1951-1954 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - G, 1950-1955 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - H, 1950-1954 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Hamburger, Phil, 1949-1954 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Hennings, Thomas C., 1949-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 6-7)
    - I through J, 1951-1954 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - K, 1951-1955 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Katcher, David, 1951, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - L, 1950-1954 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Lederer, Jules (Ann Landers), 1953-1954 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Liberal Caucus, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - M, 1949-1955 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Mendelsohn, Morris, 1950-1954 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - N, 1951-1955 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Naval Reserve--Edelstein, 1942, 1949-1952 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - O, 1950-1954 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - P, 1952-1954 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Pending Invitations, 1955 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Perlman, Philip, 1954-1954 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Q through R, 1951-1954 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - S, 1950-1955 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - T, 1951-1954 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - U through V, 1949-1954 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - W through X, 1950-1954 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Y through Z, 1951-1954 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - A, 1955-1956 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - B, 1955-1956 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - C through D, 1955-1956 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - 1955, 1957 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - E through F, 1955-1956 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Edelstein, Rivka--Includes Photographs--Some material in Hebrew, 1923, 1952-1958, (8 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 4-11)
    - Edelstein, Rivka--Includes letters of support, 1956-1957, (5 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 1-5)
    - Edelstein, Suzy--Birthday Acknowledgements, 1956-1959 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - F, 1955-1957 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - General, 1955-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 8-9)
    - G through H, 1955-1956 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - I through K, 1955-1956 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - L through N, 1955-1956, 1959 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Messages to be Acknowledged, 1955 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - O through Q, 1955-1956 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Parents, 1956-1958, (3 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 4-6)
    - R, 1955-1956 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Reply, 1955-1957 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - S through T, 1955-1956 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - U through Z, 1955-1956 (Box 51, Folder 2)
- Series IV: Office Files, 1932-1960 (1950-1955)
  Office memoranda, administrative assistants meetings, general personnel information and staff assignments and/or projects form the basis of Series IV. Edelstein’s daily calendars are included in this series; these calendars note meetings and reflect Edelstein’s to-do lists.
  - Alternative Inauguration Drafts, 1954-1955 (Box 168, Folder 1)
  - Americans for Democratic Action (ADA), 1954-1955 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Americans for Democratic Action--Westchester Speech, 1959 (Box 168, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Communism, 1938, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Articles, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Bar Association Comments, 1952-1953 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Calendars, Schedules and People to See, 1958 (Box 168, Folder 3)
  - Commander Edelstein, 1950-1957, undated (Box 168, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence
    - After September 15, 1959-1960 (Box 168, Folder 5)
    - AL, 1959 (Box 168, Folder 6)
    - Blake, Harry, 1959 (Box 168, Folder 7)
    - Christmas Cards, 1955, 1958, (2 Folders) (Box 168, Folder 8-9)
    - Congratulations, 1955 (Folder 10)
      - Current
        - General, 1959-1960 (Box 168, Folder 11)
        - Incoming, 1959-1960, (2 Folders) (Box 168, Folder 12-13)
        - Personal, 1959-1960 (Box 168, Folder 14)
    - F--General, 1958-1960, (4 Folders) (Box 168, Folder 15-18)
    - Farrell, J. T., 1959 (Box 169, Folder 1)
    - Hession, 1960, undated (Box 169, Folder 2)
    - Lehman, 1959-1960, (4 Folders) (Box 169, Folder 3-6)
    - Lehman-Edelstein, 1951-1954, (5 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 7-11)
    - Private--Latest, 1960, undated (Box 169, Folder 7)
      - Miriam, 1959, undated (Box 169, Folder 8)
      - Mom, 1956 (Box 169, Folder 9)
    - Reform Speech, 1959 (Box 169, Folder 10)
    - Shultz, Lillie, 1959 (Box 169, Folder 11)
    - Stern, J. D., 1959 (Box 169, Folder 12)
    - Sproul, Kathleen, 1959 (Box 169, Folder 13)
    - Untitled, 1959-1960, (4 Folders) (Box 169, Folder 14-17)
  - Editorial Research Reports, 1950-1953 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Health Bills--Pending, 1951 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Health Subcommittee Procedure, 1951-1952 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Immigration, 1959 December (Box 169, Folder 18)
    - Memorandums, 1959 November (Box 169, Folder 19)
  - Israel--Travel Preparations, 1959 (Box 169, Folder 20)
  - Journal Material, 1959 (Box 169, Folder 21)
  - Labor Committee--General, 1951, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Labor Management Relations, 1950 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Physically Handicapped, 1950 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Railroad Strike, 1951 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act, 1952 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Steel Strike, 1952 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Summary, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Legislative Daily --Chamber of Commerce, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Legislative Staff Memoranda, 1950, 1956, (2 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 11-12)
  - Lehman, Herbert H.--General, 1932, 1949-1951 (Folder 13)
    - Candidacy, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Lehman, Herbert H.--Personal, 1950-1955 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Voting Records, 1950-1954 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Liberal Caucus, 1955 (Box 169, Folder 22)
  - Liberal Caucus--Senators and Administrative Assistants Meetings, 1953-1955, (4 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 3-6)
  - List of Bills Introduced during 81st Congress, 1950 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Local Politics--General, 1959 (Box 169, Folder 23)
  - Memoranda, 1950-1954, (3 Folders) (Box 54, Folder 1-3)
  - Meetings on Health Legislation, 1951-1952 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Middle East Agency, 1959 (Box 169, Folder 24)
  - Nationalities Division, 1960 (Box 169, Folder 25)
  - Neuberger Memorandum, 1959 August (Box 169, Folder 26)
  - New York Advisory Council, 1959 (Box 169, Folder 27)
  - New York Bar Association Memoranda, 1954 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - New York Committee for Democratic Voters--Statement of Principles, 1959-1960, (2 Folders) (Box 169, Folder 28-29)
  - Personnel, 1951-1955 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Philadelphia Story, 1959 December (Box 169, Folder 30)
  - Speech Material and Drafts, 1950 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Speeches, 1950, 1956 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Staff Assignments, 1950 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Daily Calendars
    - Address Book--Contains Notes for Research, Undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Daily Calendars, 1951, 1953, undated, (3 Folders) (Box 55, Folder 2-4)
- Series V: Personal Research Files, 1928-1961 (1950-1959)
  The Personal Research Files were labeled as such by Edelstein with a focus on the following subjects: immigration (with an emphasis on the McCarran-Walter Act), foreign policy, civil rights, communism (with an emphasis on McCarthyism), and power. The types of materials found within these files include correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, memoranda, press releases, speeches, newsletters, publications, and maps. These records are in their original order.
  - McCarthyism
    - Freedom--General, 1952-1954, (2 Folders) (Box 56)
    - Security Risks, 1954 (Box 56)
    - Communism, 1949, 1953-1954 (Box 56)
    - Loyalty Program, 1942 (Box 56)
    - Flanders (Ralph E.) Resolution, 1954 (Box 56)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 1954 (Box 56)
  - Foreign Policy, 1949-1953
    - Asia, 1950, 1953-1955 (Box 56)
    - Indo-China, 1954 (Box 56)
  - Benton, William, 1957 (Box 56)
  - Welfare--Surplus Food Distribution Program, 1954 (Box 57)
  - Lucky Luciano, 1954 (Box 57)
  - Civil Rights--General Materials, 1952-1954, (2 Folders) (Box 57)
  - Immigration--Security, 1956 (Box 57)
  - McCarthyism, 1943, 1946-1947, 1950-1951
    - McCarthy, Joseph R.--Franking Privilege, 1953-1954 (Box 57)
    - Senate Bill for Restoration of Alien Property Seizures, 1954 (Box 57)
    - Un-American Activities, 1949, 1953-1955, (2 Folders) (Box 57)
    - Immunity, 1953-1954 (Box 57)
  - Juvenile Delinquency, 1955 (Box 57)
  - ADL Bulletin, 1959 (Box 58)
  - Anti-Discrimination Housing, 1957, 1959 (Box 58)
  - Anti-Semitism--Testimony, 1951 (Box 58)
  - Anti-Trust Laws, 1955 (Box 58)
  - Soldier Voting Laws, 1950-1951 (Box 58)
  - Atomic Energy Act, 1954 (Box 58)
  - McCarthy, Joseph R.--Senator Lehman’s Attack, 1954
    - Communism, 1950, 1953-1955 (Box 58)
    - National Security, 1950 (Box 58)
    - Foreign Students, 1950 (Box 58)
    - Trading with the Enemy Act, 1954 (Box 58)
    - Lamont, Corliss--Senate Subcommittee on Investigations, 1954 (Box 58)
  - Bank Holding Companies, 1955-1956 (Box 58)
  - Benton, William, 1956 (Box 58)
  - Bigotry, 1953-1955 (Box 58)
  - Foreign Policy--Arab States, 1950, 1953-1954 (Box 58)
  - Bronx--Speech Drafts, 1956 (Box 58)
  - Correspondence--General, 1953-1954 (Box 59)
  - Legislative Mail, 1954 (Box 59)
  - McCarthyism, 1953-1954, (2 Folders) (Box 59)
  - Disaster Insurance--Testimony, 1955-1956
    - Legislation, 1955-1956, (3 Folders) (Box 59)
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 59)
  - Disaster Funds--Ideas, 1955-1956 (Box 59)
  - Juvenile Delinquency, 1953-1954 (Box 60)
  - Defense Production Act, 1956 (Box 60)
  - Puerto Rico, 1949-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 60)
  - Foreign Policy Reports, 1951 (Box 60)
  - Americans for Democratic Action (ADA), 1958
    - Convention, 1958-1959 (Box 60)
    - Farm Policy, 1958 (Box 60)
  - Agriculture, 1953-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 60)
  - Disarmament, 1948 (Box 61)
  - Drought, 1955 (Box 61)
  - Housing, 1954-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 61)
  - Eastland, James O., 1956 (Box 61)
  - Flood Assistance for Northeastern States, 1955 (Box 61)
  - Great Lakes Basin Compact, 1955 (Box 61)
  - Subcommittee on Health, 1954 (Box 61)
  - Edelstein, Julius C. C.--Panel Debate on Immigration, 1956 (Box 61)
  - Interstate Military Compact, 1956 (Box 61)
  - Juvenile Delinquency, 1953, 1955, 1957
    - Bills Analysis, 1955 (Box 61)
    - Summary, 1955 (Box 61)
  - Milk Marketing, 1955 (Box 61)
  - Federal Trade Commission Act--McGuire Act, 1955 (Box 61)
  - Child Day Care Centers, 1954-1955 (Box 61)
  - Campaign Ideas, 1949 (Box 61)
  - Elections Rights Act, 1955 (Box 61)
  - New York Teachers Guild, 1955 (Box 61)
  - Bricker Amendment, 1954-1955 (Box 62)
  - Baruch (CUNY) Speech, 1954, 1957-1958 (Box 62)
  - United Auto Workers (UAW), undated (Box 62)
  - Negro Workers’ Conference, 1955 (Box 62)
  - Harriman, Averell, 1956 (Box 62)
  - Albert Einstein (College of Medicine of Yeshiva University) Speech, 1956 (Box 62)
  - Liberal Party Speech, 1956 (Box 62)
  - Electoral Reform, 1950, 1955-1956 (Box 62)
  - Foreign Policy--China, 1954-1955 (Box 62)
  - Wittenberg, Philip, 1956 (Box 62)
  - Sugar, 1956 (Box 62)
  - Urban League of Greater New York, 1955-1956 (Box 62)
  - Civil Rights, 1956-1957 (Box 62)
  - McCarthyism
    - Dirksen Bill--Amend Trading with the Enemy Act, 1955-1956 (Box 62)
  - Record of Congress, 1955 (Box 62)
  - Democratic Research Project, 1955-1956 (Box 62)
  - Cohen, Ben V., 1955 (Box 62)
  - Douglas Depressed Area Bill, 1956 (Box 62)
  - D’Ewart, Wesley A., 1947-1956 (Box 62)
  - Correspondence--Edelstein and Lehman, 1955 (Box 63)
  - Official Data--Names, 1953-1955 (Box 63)
  - Farm Aid Program, 1955-1956 (Box 63)
  - Bowles, Chester, 1954 (Box 63)
  - Foreign Policy
    - Defense--Speech Material, 1953-1954 (Box 63)
    - German and Japanese Reparations, 1945-1949, (3 Folders) (Box 63)
    - Defense, 1932, 1953-1954, (2 Folders) (Box 63)
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1954, 1957 (Box 64)
  - Cloture, 1957-1958 (Box 64)
  - Civil Rights, 1955, 1957-1958 (Box 64)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1957 (Box 64)
  - Electoral College, 1954-1955 (Box 64)
  - Economic Conditions, 1953, 1955 (Box 64)
  - Farrell, James T., 1953-1956 (Box 64)
  - Foreign Policy, 1954-1955
    - Quemoy Crisis, 1958 (Box 64)
    - Ghana, undated (Box 64)
    - United Nations, 1945, 1953-1954 (Box 64)
    - Defense, 1953, 1955 (Box 64)
    - Cyprus, 1956 (Box 64)
  - Brandeis University, 1954 (Box 64)
  - Bank Holding Companies, 1955 (Box 64)
  - Immigration--Migration, 1953 (Box 64)
  - Foreign Policy
    - Yalta, 1945, 1951, 1955 (Box 65)
    - Formosa, 1954-1955 (Box 65)
    - Germany, 1953-1955 (Box 65)
  - Industrial Areas Foundation, 1960 (Box 65)
  - Lehman, Herbert H.--General, 1936, 1949, 1953-1958 (Box 65)
  - United Jewish Appeal, 1958 (Box 65)
  - Civil Rights--Speeches, 1957-1958 (Box 65)
  - Education--Speeches, 1957 (Box 65)
  - The Universal Jewish Encyclopedia, 1957-1958 (Box 65)
  - Housing, 1954-1955, 1957 (Box 65)
  - Inauguration of John Kennedy, 1961 (Box 65)
  - McMahon Plan, 1956 (Box 65)
  - McCarran-Walter Act (Immigration and Nationality Act of 1952), 1954-1956 (Box 65)
  - McCarran-Walter Act (Immigration and Nationality Act of 1952), 1951, 1953-1956, (3 Folders) (Box 66)
  - Immigration, 1954-1955, 1958-1959 (Box 66)
  - Power
    - General, 1953-1955 (Box 66)
    - Niagara Falls, 1953, 1955-1957 (Box 66)
  - Right-to-Work Laws, 1958-1959 (Box 67)
  - Trade, 1953-1956 (Box 67)
  - Williams, G. Mennen, 1957 (Box 67)
  - Thomas K. Finletter Candidacy, 1958 (Box 67)
  - Federal Communications Commissioner Frieda B. Hennock, 1949-1955 (Box 67)
  - Campaign Contributions, 1958 (Box 67)
  - Political Strategy, 1953, 1956 (Box 67)
  - Humane Slaughtering Bill, 1958 (Box 67)
  - Democratic National Committee (DNC), 1957-1958, (3 Folders) (Box 67)
  - Politics, 1954-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 68)
  - Research, 1957 (Box 68)
  - Civil Liberties, 1955-1956 (Box 68)
  - Economic Conditions, 1956-1957 (Box 68)
  - Health Welfare, 1956-1957 (Box 68)
  - The Cross and the Flag, 1956-1957 (Box 68)
  - Political Memo from COPE (Committee on Political Education), 1956-1957 (Box 68)
  - Immigration, 1956-1957 (Box 68)
  - Foreign Policy Bulletin, 1952-1953, 1956-1957 (Box 68)
  - Foreign Policy--Israel, 1952, 1954-1959, (4 Folders) (Box 69)
  - Staff Memoranda, 1953, 1955-1956 (Box 69)
  - Politics, 1952, 1955-1956 (Box 69)
  - Urban League of Greater New York, 1957 (Box 70)
  - Health for Peace, 1952-1959 (Box 70)
  - Health--Speeches and Drafts, 1958-1959 (Box 70)
  - Correspondence
    - Regarding Lister Hill Bill, 1958-1959, (2 Folders) (Box 70)
    - Received by Julius Edelstein, 1957-1959 (Box 70)
    - Addressed to Lister Hill, 1958-1959 (Box 70)
    - Addressed to Howard A. Rusk, 1955, 1958-1959 (Box 70)
    - From Foundations, Colleges and Private Organizations, 1958 (Box 70)
  - Disaster Insurance--Data, 1954, 1956 (Box 70)
  - Health Insurance, 1950-1954 (Box 71)
  - Proxy Rules, 1955 (Box 71)
  - McCarthy, Joseph R.--Charges, 1953-1954 (Box 71)
  - Politics of Natural Gas, 1956 (Box 71)
  - Legislation--General, 1955 (Box 71)
  - The Decalogue Society of Lawyers, 1955 (Box 71)
  - Order of Ahepa, 1956 (Box 71)
  - Chanukah Festival, 1955 (Box 71)
  - Davis, Elmer, 1955 (Box 71)
  - McCarthyism, 1954 (Box 71)
  - Rockefeller Contributions, 1958 (Box 71)
  - Immigration--Francis D. Walter’s Proposal, 1958-1959 (Box 71)
  - Health for Peace, 1954, 1956-1959, (2 Folders) (Box 71)
  - Health for Peace, 1954, 1956-1958 (Box 72)
  - The Fund for the Republic, Inc., 1958 (Box 72)
  - Rappaport, Joseph--First Draft “Principles in Politics”, 1958
    - First Draft “Liberalism and Radicalism”, undated (Box 72)
    - “The Liberal Tactic”, undated (Box 72)
    - Assignments, 1958 (Box 72)
  - Speranza Lectures at Columbia University--Correspondence and Drafts, 1957-1958
    - Notes, 1956-1957 (Box 72)
  - Rappaport, Joseph--Drafts, Includes Speranza Notes, undated (Box 73)
  - Marxism--Notes, 1955 (Box 73)
  - Farm Unrest, Populist Party and Radicals--Notes, circa 1950s (Box 73)
  - International Affairs--Notes, circa 1950s (Box 73)
  - The Universities--Notes, circa 1950s (Box 73)
  - The Muckrakers--Notes, circa 1950s (Box 73)
  - The Depression--Notes, circa 1950s (Box 73)
  - Speranza Lectures--Second Lecture-Notes, 1957-1958
    - First Lecture-Notes, circa 1958 (Box 73)
    - General Notes, 1950s (Box 73)
  - Research for The Progressive Article, 1958 (Box 73)
  - Columbia University Degree, 1958 (Box 73)
  - Howard University Degree, 1958 (Box 73)
  - Lehman, Herbert H.--Speech on Israel, 1958 (Box 73)
  - National Democratic Club, 1958 (Box 73)
  - Research for Thomas K. Finletter Article, 1958 (Box 73)
  - Immigration--NCIC--Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 73)
  - Wager, Walter, 1953-1957 (Box 73)
  - Lowe, Charles U. (Herbert Lehman’s Nephew), 1957-1958 (Box 73)
  - Education Program, 1956-1958 (Box 73)
  - Edelberg, Herman--Notes, 1957 (Box 73)
  - Engel, Irving M., 1957 (Box 73)
  - Hession, Anne and John--Correspondence, 1957 (Box 73)
  - Civil Rights Legislation, 1957 (Box 73)
  - Correspondence--General, 1958 (Box 74)
  - Immigration Materials, 1957-1958
    - Saturday Evening Post on Immigration--Comments, 1957-1958 (Box 74)
    - NCIC--Correspondence, 1954-1955, 1957
      - Interim Project, 1958-1959 (Box 74)
      - Fiscal, 1955 (Box 74)
      - Names for Membership, 1955 (Box 74)
  - National Democratic Advisory Council (NDAC), 1957-1958 (Box 74)
  - Council on Foreign Relations--Philippines Project, 1957 (Box 74)
  - Humane Slaughtering Legislation and Shechita, 1957-1958 (Box 74)
  - Council of B’nai B’rith, 1958 (Box 74)
  - United Nations--Human Rights, 1958 (Box 74)
  - Library of Congress--Research, 1959-1960 (Box 75)
  - Incoming Lehman Correspondence, 1959 (Box 75)
  - Memoranda to Lehman, 1959 (Box 75)
  - Democratic Voters--Facts and Figures, 1959 (Box 75)
  - New York Committee for Democratic Voters--Statements, 1959 (Box 75)
  - Foreign Policy, 1958 (Box 75)
  - Correspondence--General, 1956-1959, (2 Folders) (Box 75)
  - The Cooperative Foundation, 1958 (Box 75)
  - Immigration, 1953, 1959
    - United States Committee for Refugees, 1959 (Box 75)